[Music]
hi my name is stepen B and I'm from the
developer tools team I have some code to
show you and it's going to be really
exciting but first I have to say you
can't use it not right now at least so
why do we even talk about it well you're
going to see some uptake of this feature
fairly soon uh you're going to see the
code maybe in BC apps and other places
so this is important that you know what
it's all about and maybe we can also
inspire you to use this feature in your
projects as soon as it opens so what is
it it's resources in applications
meaning you can ship your resources with
your application get the resource for
that specific application for that
specific version ship with that specific
app file there are many other ways you
can do this but this is another tool in
the tool boox for making sure that you
can ship certain Resources with your app
and now you can do it with just one
single file the app file let's look at
it so here I have an app and it's fairly
simple it doesn't have a lot of in it
but it has a new folder called resources
in that folder I have placed a few
resources I've placed a CSV file
containing some data could be demo data
could be some initialization data or
whatever and I have a picture in the
images
folder I also have a page here with some
action and it's going to be utilizing
the new function in the nav ad type
called get resource the get resource
function takes in a resource name which
is the file name including the relative
path from the root of the resources
folder so in this case the default data
CSV and it's going to take the stream
that I want this resource to be put in
so I can start using it so after calling
this function I would have the data from
the
this file in the Stream and I can start
using it this is fairly
simple I also here have an action that
will download an achievement this is
implemented in the way I would do it
prior to this feature maybe I would have
a image label here a base 64 encoded
text string that contains the image and
naturally I can easily see that this is
the right image so I can read it from
the image stream or image text into a an
outstream and change that into an
instream and then you can download that
one with the new functionality for
resources it is much easier as you can
see here I get the resource the path and
the name in the resource name and the
stream I want to put it in when I get
that I can then download that and if I
want to make sure that it's the right
one I'm pointing to here I can just
click the image over here and it works I
can see the image right here and I'm
sure it's the right one that I'm
actually sending to the client or the
customer using this okay so did any of
you wonder about this do resources
folder well I did well it's just the
default you can actually specify many
resource
folders like here I'm going to include
more resource folders I have an image
folder here which has the
images I have a data file FES folder
which has the
data and then I have the old resources
file now there's a caveat to having
multiple folders uh as resource folders
and that is that the resource name
including the path relative to the
resource folder must be unique within
the extension so if I try to compile
this extension
now it will fail and why would it fail
well if I look here it says that there
are multiple resources with the name
default data CSV and multiple resources
with the name images SL achievement
PNG so why is that well I have the
images achievement PNG here so this is
the same name as it is up here and again
here with the data I have the root for
the data files and then I have the
default data I have the root for the
resources and the default data same name
so these cannot exist in the same
extension
in this case because I wanted to move
the whole thing to a different set of
folders I can just remove the old
resources
folder and maybe delete this
one and then we should be able to
compile as simple as
that having the ability to put resources
into your app is a great new feature it
does come with some limitations let's
have a look at those so there are some
size limitations to begin with so the
max size of a resource is 1,24 kiloby
the max size of all the resources in
your extension is 16 megabytes and the
max number of resources you could have
in a single extension is
256 the resources that you put in uh
your extension are readon naturally
because you cannot alter an app package
after it has been shipped so they read
only the resources are only only
available from the extension that owns
the resource so if you want to share
resources with other extension you need
to write some kind of logic that will
expose that data Street to the other
extensions in the end the server
determines what is good and what is not
good so if you don't have um or if your
file extensions are not valid on the
server that you want to deploy it to all
the mime types checks will fail or the
virus scanning will detect something
then you will not be allowed to to
publish so make sure that you understand
these limitations but other than that
this is a nice and new feature and I'm
sure a lot of people are going to enjoy
it thank you for watching